KYLE W. SINGLETON

kwsingleton@ucla.edu

SUMMARY

Biomedical Engineering PhD with focus in medical informatics and disease modeling. Experience leading a team in program design, implementation, and deployment and facilitating communication between engineering, medical, and clinical personnel. Proficient at data cleaning and model creation with SPSS, R, and MATLAB; moderate experience with additional programming languages.

EDUCATION

University of California, Los Angeles

Los Angeles, CA

Doctor of Philosophy, Biomedical Engineering; GPA: 3.5

June 2016 (Expected)

Dissertation: Establishing methods for prognostic graphical model adjustment across observational cohorts

Advisors: Alex A.T. Bui and William Hsu

University of Virginia

Charlottesville, VA

Bachelor of Science, Biomedical Engineering; GPA: 3.1

May 2006

Minor: Computer Science

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Graduate Student Researcher

2012 - Present

UCLA Medical Imaging Informatics, Los Angeles, CA

- Supervised graduate student team, reviewing 500+ cancer cases for prognostic disease model evaluations.
- Implemented novel techniques for generalizing models between public and local data domains.

National Library of Medicine Fellow

2008 - 2012

UCLA NLM Medical Imaging Informatics Training Program, Los Angeles, CA

- Programmed and supported a tablet based system used to survey 10,000+ patients in three Los Angeles clinics.
- Completed coursework in medical informatics, statistics, and machine learning.

Post-baccalaureate Fellow 2006 - 2008

National Institutes of Health, Bethesda, MD

Section on Stroke Diagnostics and Therapeutics, NINDS

- Designed new imaging workflow, accelerating availability for stroke research tasks.
- Developed a 100 patient case MRI stroke atlas.

Undergraduate Researcher

2005 - 2006

Computational Systems Biology Lab, Charlottesville VA

Collaborated with two students to create metabolic network reconstruction of Leishmania major.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: C++, Java, R, C#, ASP.NET, MATLAB, PHP, IDL

Informatics Tools: MATLAB, R, SPSS, RapidMiner, Weka, GENIE Medical Data Standards: DICOM, HL7, XML, OWL, UMLS, HIPAA

PUBLICATIONS

Singleton KW, Speier W, Bui AAT, Hsu W. Motivating the additional use of external validity: examining transportability in a model of glioblastoma multiforme. AMIA Annu Symp Proc. 2014;2014:1930–9.

Singleton KW, Bui AAT, Hsu W. Transfer and transport: incorporating causal methods for improving predictive models. J Am Med Inform Assoc 2014;:amiajnl–2014–002968. doi:10.1136/amiajnl-2014-002968